[Music]
welcome back let's talk about individual
stocks sectors themes that you should
keep on your radar and one of them is
going to be India's defense sector
that's set to get a boost the White
House has given an in-principle approval
to General Electric to jointly produce
fighter jet engines with India's
Hindustan Aeronautics Hal with this the
final modalities of the deal are being
worked out parikshit is here with the
details parikshit
well yes this will be a mega defense
deal that will be announced when Prime
Minister Modi visits the United States
for a state visit and uh this kind of a
collaboration is really unprecedented
because this kind of a technology
transfer uh has not happened between us
and and any Ally for that matter so
having said that an impressible
agreement has been reached by both sides
what is significant to note that in 2012
GE and Hal had signed an agreement on
collaborating and co-producing jet
engines but the government was not happy
with the terms of the agreement
especially related to technology
transfer we wanted greater technology
transfer we now are given to believe by
our sources that the terms are now
agreeable to the Indian government and
this deal is much better than what had
been agreed upon in 2012 and a
substantial amount of Technology
transfer will happen to Hal uh when it
comes to the site for engine
manufacturing well an engine unit is
already functional in korapur odisha by
HL and it is possible that this could be
one of the locations for co-production
uh the technology transfer is likely to
happen in phases according to reports
and uh the modalities of the agreements
the payments uh the timings of transfer
all of that are being worked on we
believe that the Indian private sector
especially the msmes will significantly
gain from it according to sources at
least 600 msmes could benefit from
orders that HL could give as a result of
this deal
thanks a lot for that parikshit uh well
let's focus on a couple of other names
then Vivek joins us to tell us about
torrent power gmr reports as well as eil
morning Vivek well good morning you know
a few stocks on the radar first on the
list torrent power important development
for the company they've gone ahead and
signed a memorandum of understanding
with the Maharashtra government now this
is for three pump storage Hydro projects
and you know the projects would actually
entail in investment of close to 27 000
crore and the capacity of the project is
almost
5700 megawatts and it would Mark the
entry of the torrent Power Group into
the storage solution space important
note this point of time is just in mou
so it will wear it out for once the
letter of awards do come in but watch
out for this particular name it's an
important development also keep an art
for gmr airports infra uh a subsidy of
the company that is gmr Hyderabad has
gone ahead and divested a warehouse
facility located at Hyderabad airport at
an Enterprise value of close to 188
crore also keep an eye out for engineers
India Limited you know there's been a
couple of auto wins that the company has
got from both jspl as well as nalco both
of the orders at this point of time is
around 21 crore rupees
okay uh thanks very much uh for that
Vivek now uh The General Insurance data
came out this is the monthly update Yash
is uh with us uh good morning uh seems
like uh the one company which shined was
I say Lombard well that's correct uh
overall the data for the industry has
been very strong in the month of May
ICICI Lombard has managed to outperform
the industry growth the company in the
month of May has grown its premium by
about 21 on a year-on-year basis for the
two months of the current Financial year
the growth has been strong again in both
those two months so put together it's a
growth of about 18 New India Assurance
uh last Financial year was a little weak
for the company the company seems to be
finding its feet again so in May the
premium is up 18 uh underperforming the
industry but it's still better from what
it performed last Financial year for the
first two months of fi 24 the premium is
again up about eight percent star health
insurance uh the whole strategy for the
company moving from a group to retail
seems to be stabilizing and the traction
for the premium growth seems to be
coming back so in the month of May star
Health has managed to grow at about 16
on a year-on-year basis for the first
two months of fy24 the company's grown
is premium by about 20 percent on a
year-on-year basis but still
underperforming the Standalone health
insurance industry
thank you very much for that for more
stocks in the news Vivek is back with us
Vivek well some more stocks to keep on
your radar you know Bank of Maharashtra
the company has gone ahead and updated
the exchanges you know on the issue
flight as far as the qip is concerned so
they've announced the closure of the
Thousand crore qip to the successful
fundraise issue prices set at 28.5
rupees a share and some of the key
participants were LIC Aditya birla Sun
Life insurance as well as Bajaj Alliance
General Insurance company watch out for
a couple of stocks on the back of bulk
deals that happened yesterday gravita
India promoter rajat Agarwal who held
almost 47.8 percent stake at the end of
the March quarter paid almost 1.8
percent stake wire block deal yesterday
Jupiter India fund bought almost 10 lakh
shares in that particular block deal ifb
Industries you know expect some
positivity here the society General
bought almost three lectures in the
company yesterday at 800 rupees a share
okay all right thanks a lot for that
Vivek well let's do a quick recap then
of all the stocks that we just covered
for you stocks with positive news flow
include Hal torrent power your gmr
airports Engineers India ICICI Lombard
New India Assurance star Health Bank of
Maharashtra and ifb industries well
gravitar could be reacting to the news
flow that the promoter sold some stake
in yesterday's session that's about the
equity markets but let's get you an
update in terms of what's going on in
the commodity space Manisha Gupta joins
us as always to tell us exactly that
morning Manisha
now I imagine thank you for that well we
are looking at the metal prices holding
firm the gold has gained ahead of the
U.S fed meeting only because there is
now a 79 probability of a pause in rate
height on June 14. but before that on
June 13th you have the U.S consumer
inflation numbers as well coming in so
that promises to be a very eventful week
there metal price is also are moving
away from their multi-month loads we
have seen copper extend rebound from its
six month load much of the negative news
Market believes has been factored in now
while of course there is escalation in
the Russia Ukraine war and that could
continue to be on to many of these
markets but the individual fundamentals
are now coming in play with the street
believing that the metal prices perhaps
have made bottom for the very near term
also a word on the crude oil prices
where we have seen some decline in the
Asian markets right now but it
definitely is trading off its lows while
the Saudi Arabia cuts are going to be
huge the other open countries would
actually be increasing their production
especially the UAE Russia Nigeria and
Algeria and that is what is uh keeping
the prices in here the street will watch
out for the Chinese trade data that is
one number that will give you direction
for the next 24 hours
all right uh Manisha thanks very much
for that just a quick look at what Asia
is doing this morning uh so I think Hang
Seng is the only one which is really up
about one and a quarter percent uh you
know some of the Mainland Chinese
markets are flat absolutely flat uh cost
fees up about a third of a percent the
Indonesian Market is flat not very much
at all and U.S Futures are again not
showing very much by way of traction the
action of course in the US was not in
the Dow the s p or the NASDAQ but it was
in the uh broader indices like the
Russell Etc it shakes up on your screen
indicating a flatish kind of start uh 23
24 hour points is what we have with
still more than 30 minutes to go for
that pre-open session they've been
choksi is with us if KR choksi will talk
specific stocks uh and uh what he makes
at the market we'll also have the
management of man infra construction
joining in to talk about their next
luxury residential project in Mumbai and
the business Outlook as they see stay
with us
[Music]
thank you
foreign